hello I'm dr. Brian Frazer and in this
tutorial I'm going to show how to use
git within eclipse to create a
repository and push that repository
we're going to start by working with a
local repository and then moved working
with get up
so to begin with i have created a basic
java project
this doesn't have to be a job a project
that could be any project you like
android see whatever and inside of this
I've got the files that I you know might
be starting with I've initially got here
a main file that's a class
all it does is it instantiates sales
data object calls them sink a simple
method down here and then calls data .
display which calls into this function
here in my data object
oh it does at the moment is Prince a
message to the screen through the
tutorials later on we're going to be
editing these files and seeing how they
change but for the moment it for the
time being if i run this we can see down
here is simply print out the two
messages from this file and then execute
sale data and Prince of that message
nothing special ok so now what happens
if other people want to work on this
well I need to start sharing this i need
to start working with get other tools
such as svn or CSV would also work
this is also about get so let's see what
happens so I'm first going to right
click on the project and then go down to
team and then share project team share
project here
I then have the gip provider and then i
select what do I want to do with it well
I've got to first create a local
repository to work with
i'm going to create the default path is
probably fine for accessing that and i'm
going to give it a name so let's call
this
sales tool repository and just for fun
i'm going to call it local sales to a
repository
just so we know what we're working on
you probably don't need the word local
in yours
I'm not going to bother providing a path
in the repository that's fine i'll just
say finish because this whole project is
going to be the report the repository
now what just happened hmm
we don't really see any changes going on
so what I want to do is I want to bring
up some extra views i'm going to go to
window show views and then go to other
under well first off I'm going to going
to get so if you want to get I want to
look at the repositories and the staging
area is actually going to be handy later
so you bring that up and the one other
one I want is the perspective the
history center team select history
let's start by looking here under my
repositories
what have I done well I created my local
sales repository 20 repository and now
i'm working with that we can see here
that I've got branches
well I got nothing really going on here
at the moment and I've got no remotes
the references is not much of anything
so what I need to do is we need to do my
very first commit to go back into my
file here now i happen to have already
up here my toolbar
i'm gonna show you how to get this get
toolbar you go to windows and then
customize perspective
we're not yet showing the get ability so
you have to come under command group
availability and then put a checkmark
and get click ok and that's not going to
give you the get when you hear that you
can work with plus the toolbar here at
the top that I liked so I got my files
all ready to go
all ready to be checked into my
repository helps i'm showing something
here I just tried saving the file but it
tells me here that doesn't follow longer
exists
it's actually been moved I had these
files open to begin with so I'm gonna
have to close them here and now when I
open them again
it's gonna be in a different place if I
right click on this and go to properties
we can see here that it's now moved to
under my get sub folder so it's actually
moved my project
that's ok so i'll move those up
save those and now what I want to do is
I want to commit so i could go here
right click go to team and then I could
go to commit
I'll try that to begin with I give her a
message
initial check in sales tool provided
author so forth
this email address of using get help may
be publicly available so you might want
to use one that you don't really care
about
so these are the files that i can choose
to check in
I like this button here on the right add
them all except I don't really want to
add them all i want to add most of them
so i'm going to go through and remove
those I don't
there's no sense in checking in my
compiled class files they just be a pain
to manage merges on later
so I'm going to keep those out of my
repository so to begin with I'm just
going to say don't check in the class
files but checking everything else
so I've got my project files the
classpath project and some settings
plus I've got all my source files you
might also have resources like text
files HTML files documents or even
images
I guess they commit now what's happened
is you notice down here under my local
repository under branches local I have
this thing called master master is the
main line that we're building on
so master is now created
now the next thing i want to do is I
want to be able to say well let's push
this up if i go to my web page gain hit
f3
sorry i haven't been there yet i have
not yet created anything online
so nothing is yet gone on to my get hub
repository
so if i go into history here if I right
click on my project and i think there's
a show in button
maybe just off the screen we bring this
up we've it all right click on that
try to gain right click show in history
and now we've got here on the right-hand
side all the history of my project
this is going to be critical we're going
to really want to look at this a lot
later on but let's start off by going up
to the remote server so i want to go
into here and i want to say i want to
create a remote
now how am I going to do that
well I need to first going to get help
so you bring my browser
I'm going to get hub com i've already
logged in with the user ID they're free
to create and i'm going to create a new
repository so use this button down here
new repository we can pick a name for it
let's call the sales tool
I can provide a description i want i'm
going to make it public so it's free and
then create a repository so you can see
here and I've create a repository
there's nothing in it
what I really want is I want this URL
i'm going to copy this this is the way
that I'm going to get access into my
github repository from within eclipse
so I'm going to get back into eclipse
creating a remote reference repository
to connect to your name and origin
that's the standard name of what we do
talk about the upstream repository so
we'll leave with origin
i'm going to change the URL here so it
brings in whatever I had copied already
it fills in the host and the extra
pieces of information from that I need
to put in my user ID and my password you
can choose to save this is secure
storage just don't have to type it in
every time
so a quick finish now we've got this
safe here now
this ref mapping is actually quite
interesting
I'm going to want to add one here so I
could go through ad type it in that's a
little more , up harder than I want i'm
going to go through the advanced because
it happens to fill in everything for me
so I say what source drifter I want it
to be ye what do I want to work on out
and work on this master this master
branch is really the one I'm going to be
pushing so it's like master here
destination it automatically fills in
the master there and add spec that's
really the only thing i want to push up
to my repository is a specification in
the origin configuration
sounds good click finish and i'm going
to save here i could say save and push
but let's do it in two steps going to
first save
expand remote here we see we have the
origin which is good that the one I
really want to work with and then i can
for example push to get over this one
with the red arrow put pointing to it
I could right click and say push let's
try that
push the road push so it's done this
pushed to local sales -
origin so it pushed to the local the
origin rather of it click OK
i'm going to switch back to my web
browser hit f5 to reload and we'll see
that we've actually push something up to
the server
so Brian Frazer four minutes ago push
sales tools
so go into this i can see all the files
that i just checked in my source CA and
here's my main file just like we had
down on my program
ok so now I've done that now as a few
things are going to want to do let's
just make another change and walk you
that once more this isn't how r normal
going to make changes we'll see how
later on to do that but let's just put
something in here
test 1 i'm going to run it to make sure
it works
well we got an error so cancel that what
do we got well print
LOL and we want you to run that with
ctrl f11 we can see here it actually ran
it's fantastic now i want to check this
in
so i can use up here I can check in now
i'm going to say first change like
normally had something more description
so a
add a simple output change
I could say commit and push but I'm
going to work on just two steps and
stages hearing as they commit it now
pushes it up to my local repository so
we can see here that the latest thing
pushed up with that and I don't yet have
it on
I open up references this is the yeah
that's references there so the remote
doesn't yet have a so i can say i can
right click on this and give us a push
branch so there's only one good one
and it pushes it up here we can see the
different changes being pushed
that's now gone up so let's check it I
go ahead of five this file reload so we
can see here that indeed my change
actually made it to the server
so that's a very simple change after
having checking the project now we
notice that it kept asking for you want
what files you want to submit and here
we see on my project Explorer that
there's not listing those extra bin
files that we had
i'm going to switch to my navigator tab
if you don't have this you can go to
window show view go to other and then
say now
navigator it's like that and we'll come
up with a navigator shows me the actual
files that are present
let's get this bin folder with a
question mark meaning that it doesn't
actually know it's not being checked in
to get going to right click on my whole
bin folder I'm going to team
I'm gonna say ignore so now it's going
to ignore that file
note that it actually created get . get
ignore and it simply lists all the files
that are going to be ignored
so you can add in here you got any other
generated files you want to ignore
now this is a file like any other let's
go ahead and commit that to the
repository so I'm going to
go up here and i'm going to say commit
added ignore
with that in and I'm going to push now I
can just go here push changes upstream
it says upstream it kind of knows that
it always defaults are going to the
origin
it knows the upstream location and so
now it's going to push that up to the
appropriate repository online and the
next time we go to check in
it's not going to ask hey you want to
check in those files you asked to ignore
you want to set it up the ignore
carefully because then all of your team
members will also get the same ignore
file that's handy because then nobody
else inadvertently checks in for example
a half- generated exe files
ok so what we see what we have so how to
using the tool or team and then the
share project we saw how to share it
with a local repository so in here and
we saw how to push that up to the
remotes
now as it turns out we see here that
it's actually tracking the loading
if you want more information check the
comments below it will give you a link
to other get tutorials in this sequence