hey there today we're going to be
learning about github and we're also
going to be learning about source
control if you guys I'm pretty sure
you're sitting in one of probably three
boats right now
one you have no idea what get hub is no
one's talked about it you've not heard
about it and i'm here to talk about it
because it's really important and pretty
much any professional company is going
to be using github or something like it
and will expect you to know it or you're
sitting in a boat number two you've
heard about it you know about it but you
haven't learned to get its kind of been
a black box we're going to make that an
easy thing to learn today and step three
you person number three you've may be
used sub subversion or CVS you know what
source control is you just want to learn
get hub
this might not be the tutorial for you
because i'll be getting a little bit
more ground level stuff here but you
learn it all
it just might be a little bit slower
paced for you so let's get into real
quick what is source control
why is it important why is every
employer value it
let's say there's two people right here
pretend my screen is divided here and
these are two guys up here we have John
and down here we have Bobby
so let's say this is the exact same file
open on John's computer open on Bobby's
computer and John edits this thing and
he has an item in here he adds an li and
he adds sand
now how does Bobby get that change if
Bobby's already made five changes he's
added his own stuff down here now you've
got to get together and getting a room
you've got to open up both copies of the
file it gets messy as you can imagine in
a company of 10 people it gets messy
almost instantly
what do you do another common prop
problem is people overriding people
stuff the leading people stuff having to
check out files
there's really no clean way to do it
people have to be able to work on the
same files at the same time without
hours and hours of wasted work and
unnecessary communication that's where
source control came in
what git hub will do or get will do for
you is you open a get project and that
keeps track of all the change
is that you make so when I make this
change it knows that I've made this
change and then i can at any time
connect and find out anyone elses
changes
so let's say Bobby's added I forget what
it is rope
I don't know why use rope if you're
hitting a brick wall at any time I can
sync up to the repository and it will
pull in the fact that Bobby made and
saved this change and so then I won't
lose any work
it'll just automatically boom boom boom
throw in everyone else's changes and at
the same time he can do the same thing
he can sync up to the repository and get
my changes every once in a while you get
what's called a merge conflict and
that's when both i have edited this line
i'm going to call it a good mortar and
he's going to call this mortar and if he
saves that and then I sync up to the
repository
it's not going to know who's right it's
just going to know i changed it and
Bobby change it so I'll get something
like this depending on what kind of
source control i'm using I'll get your
version something that looks and output
like this and it will say it's a
conflict and also have to go okay
hmm one of these is the right one which
one is the right one
Bobby change this I change this
oh I know what i'll do i'll go more good
mortar
there we go and then I'll get rid of all
this junk and I'll save my file and now
I had to manually merge changes that
will still happen sometimes but get hub
will flag for you
everything that both people have done
the way to minimize having to do that
because that is kind of a pain in the
rear and there's really no way around it
is to make sure you have good
communication on generally who's working
on what tasks and that shouldn't happen
very often and when it does it shouldn't
be much bigger than what I just kind of
showed you right there
so let's get into get hub let's get into
an actual project and how we're going to
set this up and manage this first thing
you'll need to do is you need to get
github installed on your
Peter and you'll need to sign up for
github account so go to github com and
sign up for an account its free and then
also go to Mac github com or windows .
github com and install the github
application that will take care of
everything else you need for your right
there and it will give you a visual
application which i will tell you not to
use
so this is the visual application it
will give you
it's super easy really easy to get
started but a lot of employers look down
on it because lots of people use this is
a crutch instead of actually learning
the command line the command line is not
hard it's about five commands a lot of
people just avoid it like the plague is
seeing a black screen freaks them out
but we're going to get past that fear
today and have a great time with it so
i'm going to go ahead now and create a
new repository think of repository
equals project whatever I already did
one called get tutorial as a test so new
gets test so i'm making a repository
called new get tests and the only thing
I'm going to check here is initialized
this repository with the readme and that
allows me to clone it right away
I'll show you what that means so you see
it made a new repository for me called
nougat test
I already have my first file which is
called read me and all the readme has is
this what the readme is its kind of any
instructions
you're going to give to people who use
this repository it's automatically
displayed when you open up the
repository so I'm going to do here is
I'm going to copy this clone URL
this is what I will use to get it on my
machine ok that's all i need to do
forget hub
so now i'm going to use yes the dreaded
command line
lots of you guys have been avoiding this
because you're terrified of it you don't
know what to do with it and we're going
to get into this today so if you're on
Mac you only need to know like three
commands to actually use this thing and
then get hubs five commands and if
you're on Windows same thing to open it
with Mac you go to utilities
applications utilities terminal
and then to open it on windows you're
going to go run and type CMD and hit
enter
so basically CD is your change directory
command so if i go CD . i'm going to go
up a directory
I just went from documents into will so
now i can go CD back into documents
there we go i can also go see . nauman
users i can go CD will documents and I
that's basically CD that's your first
command and the other one is going to LS
and that will show you a listing of all
the files in your directory if you're on
Windows it's going to be dir unless you
have fake linux mac commands installed
so you can see I have a few files in my
documents thing not much what I'm going
to do is I want to put the repository
and documents so I'm going to go get
clone and i'm going to paste that URL
that i copied clone is your first get
command
well that does is it takes that
repository and it copies the whole thing
down and puts it in a folder called its
name by its name so now if i hit LS you
can see that i have a folder called new
get tests OCD new get tests and LS
I've got read me . md that's my only
file
okay that's about all i'm going to do
for now let me go ahead and add that
folder to my project here and New get
test
there we go so now I've got my folder
and I can do away with you
you're not necessary anymore actually
what you're saying and what I'm going to
do down here is let's say John Bob does
the same thing he's going to go get
clone not read me md this URL
jon is also working on our project so he
also is going to clone it you notice
I've cloned into a different folder so
you can actually have the same folder on
your computer in 20 different places and
this one's in my github folder here we
go
so now we both have the repository here
and i'm going to go ahead over here on
the top and I'm going to make a new file
I'm going to save it as
as you get tests will call index dot
HTML and let's make something here real
quick
let's make our first I list here we'll
just kind of recreate what we had bricks
bricks and mortar let's just make it a
list of two items i'll save it and you
notice i got index 2.html there and John
still doesn't have anything because he's
not he's just working on his own
let me go ahead and I'll make a new file
here for John and we'll call it
index 2.html
well just make it will just do this you
l must leave it like that
so John's got index - I've got index and
we're both working on the project and
that's all the progress we've made
so here are you ready here's we've got
our first command which is get clone
that's going to pull her any repository
in using its URL
our next get command is get status so
this is going to show us what's
different between us and get hub up in
the sky right now so all that's
different now is there's an untracked
file we have created file called
index.html get up has no clue that this
file exists
so I'm going to do right now is I'm
going to do get ad which means we're
going to add any changes or any new
files or whatever by name so add index
dot HTML
so now we've said Kate put this guy into
our project if I do get status again
you'll notice that it's now a change to
be committed we have a new file index
dot HTML
so now all i have to do is I've added it
I can go get to commit
which means I'm locking it in to the
repository get commit at dash M means
i'm giving it a message and the message
is going to be in quotes
add it
index dot HTML there we go so now it's
committed but it's still on my machine
it's locked into the repository but it's
not synced up to get hub . com yet so
all we have to do to get it to do a sink
is get push
that's going to take anything on our
machine and push it up to get hub . com
so now if i go to github com and i
refresh you'll notice i have index dot
HTML
so there we go now it's up there I'm
going to hide this
and so now if this guy here goes get
pull which is so push pushes up to
github com and pull is going to pull
down from github com whoops I'm not the
right directory CD space new get test
get pull these commands will only work
when you're in the directory of your
github repository because you can have a
hundred different repositories on your
computer so i didn't get pole and you
see it pulled in index dot HTML
now I've got them both so now John's
going to do is john scott this guy and
i'm also going to add an item to my list
here
sand so now if I do get status
I see two things i've modified index dot
HTML and I have an untracked file myself
so I can you get ad index dot HTML and
you'll see that now if I do get status
the changes for commit our that i've
modified this guy up sorry wrong one
changes to be committed that modified
this and i still have an untracked file
that's not ready to be committed
so I can do get ad index to another
thing you can do is you can you get ad .
which is going to do everything in your
directory or you can you get hat add -
capital A which is going to do get at
all so I'm going to get add a an alpha
to get status you see that I've got two
files ready to go
one its modified one that's brand new
and i'm going to do a terribly generic
git commit which is a bad idea made
changes
that's not useful to anyone but oh well
so I've added committed
I'm going to push and now over here i'm
going to pull gets pull
but before I yes I get full there we go
and so now notice I've got index - and
my index one automatically has all the
updated changes if five different people
were working on these files and i did a
poll it get everybody's changes as long
as they push them up
so that's kind of how it works you'll
notice the commands are too bad so far
we've got get status get ad get commit
get pushed it pole
Matt's kind of your basics in to get hub
there's about ten commands in total if i
just type get it will show me kind of
all the commands that i can use and kind
of what they do and that's pretty much
the beginning of github so let's talk
about a little bit about workflow
how do you actually do this so one thing
I'll do is when i come in at the
beginning of each day
i'm going to start off by doing a get
pull want to make sure I get everybody's
updates from all you know
last night the rest of the day hey
already up today great
I'm going to make my changes . that ah
this isn't water anymore
it's now called I don't know something
else quikrete think that's how you spell
it made that change death at a
and so now I'm ready to push my changes
up i'm going to add everything made more
more specific
got it got all my changes done I'm ready
to sync up all my work to the repository
I'll do this with every kind of
incremental piece of work I do i will
probably add commits all throughout the
day and then every few hours in the day
I'm going to make sure i'm in sync to
make sure I don't get away far office
stuff
let's create what's called a merge
conflict here instead of mortar i'm
going to put i'm going to change this to
more mortar
I think we already went through that
example so get at a git commit
let's say down here on the bottom what's
this guy's name again Bobby Bobby just
made a change on a line that i made a
change on and so now when I do a git
pull
I says conflict merge conflict in index
dot HTML
you have to fix the conflicts and then
commit the result
basically you've both changed these
lines and that look first this looks
like crazy freaking out what the heck do
I do with this
all it's telling me is his head which is
what I'm on
we made this change to this line and
somebody else made this change
so what do we do about it I'm not smart
enough to know you've got to figure this
out
it's not too bad i just look at the two
lines and say okay
he was adding more which is our
company's way of saying we need to get
more than one so I'm just going to do
more quikrete i'm going to kind of
manually merge those lines together or
I'm going to just say no quick crees all
right line
he didn't really know what he's talking
about we don't ever say more anyway i
manually make the decision i delete all
the helper things that it gave me save
my file and now i just hit get commit
with nothing in there
let's get add a git commit forgot to add
it
you notice it said ok now its continuing
my merge branch of Master and by the way
if you ever accidentally hit commit
without a message or anything you'll get
this screen you won't figure out how to
get out of it
you hit escape : WQ to save it escaped :
WQ
there you go merge branch master yes
escape : WQ is the most complicated part
of everything we're going to learn today
just write that one down it takes a long
time and I'm always forgetting it
escaped : WQ is how you get out of a
full-blown commit
I'll show you real quick just what that
was so let's say I made a change
now I can modify the index get add a
it's commits if you ever just hit commit
without the dash M
it's going to open up this same thing
it's for a full-blown message is what it
is it's for a multiline message
there you go so that's kind of what that
was it was like a multi-line commit
message once again escaped
: WQ enter and there you go get push and
now he can do it get pole you can 5 out
and find out that i've deleted that line
there you go and that is your intro to
get hub once again get commit get add a
get pushed it pull
that's about it have a great day